# CESAR SANCHEZ-VEGAS

Solutions Architect

832 - 439 - 3705



Cesar.sanchezvegas82@gmail.com



Atlanta, GA



linkedin.com/in/cesarsanchezvegas



## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Full stack software developer and experienced pre-sales executive with proven history of achieving targets and delivering results. Deep knowledge and understanding about core banking platforms, digital banking platforms and check processing. Proficient in front-end and back-end technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Angular JS, Firebase, Node JS and MySQL.

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

**Excellent Communication Skills** 

Effective Communicating Technical Solutions

Strong Problem-Solving abilities

Strategic Planning and Delivery

**Analytics Skills** 

Technical Expert

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## SOLUTIONS ENGINEER AND LATIN AMERICA SALES EXECUTIVE

VSoft Corp | Duluth, GA | 2016 - Present

- Prepare and deliver presentations and demonstrations to prospective and existing customers as the Subject Matter Expert for VSoft Core Banking system for US activities and VSoft Check Processing Platform for LATAM activities.
- Answer Requests for Information, Requests for Proposal and create Business Proposals, Statements of Work, and any other documents required during the sales cycle for VSoft Core Banking and VSoft Check Processing initiatives.
- Perform gap and system architecture analysis on Core Banking systems such as Fiserv-DNA, Fiserv-Portico, Finastra-Sparak, Corelation-Keystone, and other Cores. Report findings and create a new proposed system architecture to prospective customers during the sales cycle.
- Design, define and document new-to-market VSoft Remittance, VSoft Real-Time Signature Verification and VSoft Positive Pay Solutions after creating a competitors' analysis and gathering customers' requirements.
- Define requirements (BRDs, SRDs, etc.) to integrate with customers and partner solutions either through API Calls, REST web services or extract files.

#### BRANCH MANAGER, VP

JPMorgan Chase Bank N.A. | Atlanta, GA | 2014 - 2016

- Managed daily operations of a \$60 million branch banking facility, including developing strategies to increase deposit and investment balances, managing the monthly budget and recruiting/retention of team of employees.
- Exceeded goals and expectations in all measurable categories while growing balances by 25% YOY.

# CESAR SANCHEZ-VEGAS

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**System Integration** 

System Architecture

**Banking Technology Specialist** 

Junior Engineer

**Development Test Scripts** 

Application testing and troubleshooting

### **EXTRAS**

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English and Spanish

## **EXPERIENCE** CONTINUED

- Evaluated branch performance and implemented actions to ensure objectives were met while strengthening and growing customer relationships through a commitment to quality service.
- Trained team to focus on Customer Satisfaction improving behaviors, which resulted in the branch being among the top 10% in customer service satisfaction nationwide (Q4 100% Satisfaction)

### ASSISTANT BRANCH MANAGER, AVP

JPMorgan Chase Bank N.A. | Atlanta, GA | 2010 - 2014

- Managed, coached and developed sales and service team to maintain an operationally sound branch (Total Net Operating Losses for three consecutive years – the lowest in the market.)
- Executed and provided guidance on sales activities with sales and service team helping increase balances and referrals.
- Consistently among the top 10% YOY in customer service satisfaction.

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

#### **CODING BOOTCAMP PROJECTS:**

GitHub account:

https://github.com/cesvg123

Group Project:

 My role was to get the APIs connected and extract and present the proper data on the HTML pages.

https://jwmann13.github.io/pain-management-portal/index.html Personal Profile Project:

- The personal profile project has been a continues effort since the bootcamp started.

https://cesvg123.github.io/Updated-Portfolio/index.html

## **EDUCATION**

CODING BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE: Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA – 02/2020

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN FINANCE: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA – 12/2011

B.B.A. IN ECONOMICS: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA – 12/2008

B.B.A. IN FINANCE: University of Houston/Downtown, Houston, TX – 05/2006